# ALAA JERBI

+21655584876 | hello@alaajerbi.com | alaajerbi.com | github.com/alaajerbi

#### SUMMARY

Student in Software Engineering with experience in application development and design. Fluent in English with excellent writing and interpersonal skills. Passionate with building products that are not only useful, but also aesthetically pleasing. Energetic and motivated with strong work ethic in team or individual settings.

#### **EDUCATION**

National Institute of Applied Sciences and Technology

Sept. 2016 – June. 2021

Software Engineering Degree, minor in DevOps

Farhat Hached High School

Baccalaureate in Computer Science (highest average in Ben Arous state)

Sept. 2016 – June. 2016

#### EXPERIENCE

#### Freelance Full-stack JavaScript Developer

March 2019 – Present

Fiverr

- Built web apps for clients with React, Express, NodeJS, and MongoDB
- Converted static websites into Single Page Applications using React

# **Mobile Developer Intern**

March 2020 – August 2020

**PYNTOPYN Technologies** 

- Developed a mobile application using React Native and Expo SDK to scan food products barcode and get their nutritional values and labels
- Fixed responsiveness issues by creating custom auto-scaling components
- Implemented Google OAuth for user authentication
- Designed the application mockups with InVision Studio

## **UI/UX Designer Intern**

July. 2019 - Aug. 2019

Kollab Agency

- Designed mockups for an e-wallet mobile application using Adobe XD
- · Converted design to HTML and CSS components

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, PHP, Java, Dart, Bash, HTML/CSS, SQL

Technologies: ReactJS, React Native, Flutter, Angular, NodeJS, Express, openCV, Tensorflow, MongoDB, MySQL

Tools: Git, Docker, Heroku, VS Code, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Figma

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

**Chatrooms** | React, Express, NodeJS, Socket.io, Git

https://github.com/alaajerbi/chatrooms

A real-time chat app that allows you to create private chat rooms that get destroyed after a time limit

- Built the frontend and routing using React
- Implemented the chat mechanism using Express, Node and Socket.io
- Deployed the server on a Heroku dyno instance

**Hacker News Clone** | React, HackerNews Algolia API, Git

https://github.com/alaajerbi/hackernews-clone

A clone of the hackernews website

- Built the frontend and routing using React
- · Implemented search functionality with highlighted search keywords on result pages
- Deployed the application on Github pages